<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Antonio Raiola</title>
    <link>https://raiolartw.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Antonio Raiola</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://raiolartw.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chi-squared Goodness-of-fit Tests for Conditional Moment Restrictions</title>
      <link>https://raiolartw.github.io/research/chi-squared-goodness-of-fit-tests-for-conditional-moment-restrictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raiolartw.github.io/research/chi-squared-goodness-of-fit-tests-for-conditional-moment-restrictions/</guid>
      <description>$\chi^2$ tests are proposed for assessing the specification of regression models or general conditional moment restrictions (CMR). The data is partitioned based on the explanatory variables into several cells, and the $\chi^2$ tests evaluate whether the difference between the observed average of the dependent variable and its expected value under the model specification, within each cell, arises by chance. In contrast to existing omnibus procedures, $\chi^2$ tests are pivotal and fairly insensitive to the curse of dimensionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counterfactual Analysis Based on Grouped Data: Application to Poverty and Material Deprivation</title>
      <link>https://raiolartw.github.io/research/counterfactual-analysis-based-on-grouped-data-application-to-poverty-and-material-deprivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raiolartw.github.io/research/counterfactual-analysis-based-on-grouped-data-application-to-poverty-and-material-deprivation/</guid>
      <description>We propose to estimate the counterfactual decomposition of distributional statistics using aggregated data. The counterfactual estimation is a two-step procedure: first, we aggregate the data; then, we evaluate a mean (or a regression) in each group and re-weight them for the groups&amp;rsquo; composition of a reference population. Our approach allows for a path-independent detailed decomposition, highlighting the contributions of each group and each characteristic. We propose using a data-driven method to form the groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Nontrivial Power of Panel Slope Homogeneity Tests in the Presence of Grouped Patterns</title>
      <link>https://raiolartw.github.io/research/on-nontrivial-power-of-panel-slope-homogeneity-tests-in-the-presence-of-grouped-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raiolartw.github.io/research/on-nontrivial-power-of-panel-slope-homogeneity-tests-in-the-presence-of-grouped-patterns/</guid>
      <description>While the literature on grouped patterns in panel data analysis has received significant attention, little to no results are available on pretesting grouped patterns. In this paper, we show that available tools for testing slope homogeneity in panels can be used for this purpose. We provide local power analysis and highlight important limitations of the available testing frameworks. A short Monte Carlo study supports our theoretical findings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
